<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?> 

<diary>
	<entry date="03.09.2003">
		Left home at 5 a.m., which should allow enough time to
		get to the airport and check in. The car starts acting
		strange after refilling fuel and motor oil. When I pull over the motor
		is full of spilled oil. I decide it's probably not a good idea to 
		continue with this car.
		<p>
		Luckily at this moment Mr. and Mrs. Schnaiter from the black forest
		are taking a break at the same rest area. They are also going to the
		Hahn airport for their flight, and are kind enough to let me go with
		them. I take all the expensive stuff from the car and hope it won't
		be towed while I'm on holidays.
		</p>
		<p>
		I make it to the airport just in time, which is good since Ryanaird doesn't
		give refunds. The rest of the journey is uneventful. Elin is picking me
		up in Stockholm, we take a quick stroll through the city and have some
		food.
		</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="04.09.2003">
		After breakfast I visit the lab with Elin, in order to send mail to my
		brother and flatmates and to let them know the status of my car. 
		<p>
		I spend the rest of the day walking the city, take a tour of the city hall
		(this is where the Nobel Price dinner is held every year, among other things)
		and have a look at the old town.
		</p>
		<p>
		I pick up Elin from the lab, we rent a video for the evening. Too bad there
		aren't any swedish movies subtitled in a language that I can read.
		</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="05.09.2003">
		After getting up I spent some time with my travel lecture (Haruki Murakami: 
		The Wind-Up Bird Chronicle). After that I go to the Skansen, which is 
		some kind of big open-air museum, where they put swedish houses of different
		times and regions. The houses are inhabited by folks dressed up in costumes
		from the era. When you enter one of the homesteads there will be a farmer
		inside, or the "wife" doing knitwork. They even have a small town with a
		church, a bakery and a post office. 
		<p>
		At the Skansen they also have a collection of nordic animals. I was just
		right for the feeding, so I went around and had a look at all those wolves,
		bears, elks and owls. I missed the aquarium, though.
		</p>
		<p>
		In the evening we went to a mainstream techno-stylie club with some friends
		of Elin from the lab, but it wasn't really groundbreaking.
		</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="06.09.2003">
		Went shopping for clothes in S&#246;dermalm, but without much success. Elin had
		to do her washing that afternoon (obviously you have to stick to prearranged 
		times to clean you clothes), so I returned to my book. 
		<p>
		We spent the rest of the night talking and watching evil movies from the 
		eighties and even more evil soap operas from just now on the telly.
		</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="07.09.2003">
		Went for a boat ride into the Sch&#auml;ren (the small islets just off the coast).
		The weather was bright, although it was already quite cold and windy out on the
		water. We found a sunny spot on one of the islands, however, where you could
		still enjoy the sun.
		<p>
		After getting home we went to a restaurant for some K&#246;ttbullar (swedish 
		meatballs).
		</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="08.09.2003">
		I went to the national museum today, which had a nice exhibition on swedish design
		of the 20th century. They also had a special exhibition on art with animals, which
		was quite good. One of the highlights was a booth with contemporary chinaware from
		one swedish factory. They had the same china which we used when I was in Sweden as
		a kid. (My father gave me one of the cups after I got home). The rest of the museum
		was pretty much standard fare.
		<p>
		Later on I sat down at the water, to get my postcards done. I also visited Elin at
		the lab to sent off an email to Patrick in order to get some help for returning the
		car.
		</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="09.09.2003">
		Another day of museums. This time it was the technical museum, which was mildly 
		interesting but featured to few "hands-on" exhibits for my taste. At least they
		had free internet terminals, which allowed me to check my mail again. I still
		spent too much time in that museum, so I was to late for the nordic museum.
	</entry>
	<entry date="10.09.2003">
		Elin took me to the bus at 3am in the morning. The journey went smoothly, although
		it took me quite a while until I was back home on public transport. I got
		Patrick to tow my car to the nearest garage. It was still the same as I'd left
		it, but had to be expensively repaired.
	</entry>
</diary>
