<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
    Document   : files_rpg.xml.xml
    Created on : 28. August 2003, 20:09
    Author     : daniel
    Description:
        Purpose of the document follows.
-->

<downloadlist>

<title>Role Playing Material</title>
<introduction>
These are materials for several pen-and-paper roleplaying games that I have run.
If you find something in here useful or even start to make additions to this 
material, I'll be happy to her from you.
<p>
I have put all of this material under some Open Content License, allowing you to 
freely use and change the work. Each download contains either a license file,
or a copyright notice at the end of the text that indicates under which license
the work is published. Most of the text in english language is covered by the
<a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/1.0/">Creative Commons
Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike license</a>, while the german stuff is
under the <a href="http://www.uvm.nrw.de/opencontent">Open Content Lizenz</a>. 
Note that this licenses <b>do not</b> apply to this web site itself and that the
license information included in the Download is always the authoritative one!
</p>
</introduction>

<item>
    <title>Hard Life</title>
    <description>
    A girl is fighting for her place in a hostile world, against overwhelming 
    odds. Without help, she'll be lost.<br/>
    I made this as a "quickshot" adventure, set in the world of the "Blue Planet"
    game by Biohazard. Character sheets have been provided for the first edition
    of the game, however "Blue Planet" has since been republished by Fantasy 
    Flight games with new rules.<br/>
    The scenario contains hints at child abuse, use this at your own discretion.
    </description>
    <link target="downloads/hard_life.ps">PostScript</link>
    <link target="downloads/hard_life.pdf">PDF</link>
    <link target="downloads/hard_life.tex">LaTex source</link>
</item>

<item>
    <title>Peaceful Relations</title>
    <description>
    Remote farms are ruthlessly attacked by unknown raiders. Can the slaughter
    be stopped before an open war breaks out.<br/>
    These are notes and character descriptions for an adventure that I run
    as part of a "Deadlands - Lost Colony" game. The scenario could be adapted
    to almost any wild west/outback setting.
    </description>
    <link target="downloads/deadlands.pdf">PDF</link>
    <link target="downloads/deadlands.tex">LaTex source</link>
</item>

<item>
    <title>Feng Shui Characters</title>
    <description>
    A collection of character descriptions I made up for a "Feng Shui" campaign.
    </description>
    <link target="downloads/fs_characters.pdf">PDF</link>
    <link target="downloads/fs_characters.tex">LaTex sources</link>
</item>

<item>
    <title>Feng Shui Snippets - The mysterious plans of Dr. Shon-Goo</title>
    <description>
    A series of notes and plot ideas I made for a "Feng Shui" campaign. Can the
    players stop Evil Overlord Dr. Shon-Goo from taking over the world?
    </description>
    <link target="downloads/fengshui.zip">PDF and Latex sources in one .zip file</link>
</item>

<item>
    <title>Feng Shui equipment list</title>
    <description>
    A few nifty new items (guns and cars) for use with the "Feng Shui" 
    roleplaying game.
    </description>
    <link target="downloads/fengshui_gear.pdf">PDF</link>
    <link target="downloads/fengshui_gear.tex">LaTex source</link>
</item>

<item>
    <title>A history of the Dark Ages</title>
    <description>
    A short timeline of events in medieval Europe. I made this for a "Vampire"
    campaign, but it's all "real" stuff and may be used for any game. No
    warranties for historical correctness, though...
    </description>
    <link target="downloads/da_history.pdf">PDF</link>
    <link target="downloads/da_history.tex">LaTex sources</link>
</item>

<item>
    <title>gameXF - a roleplaying XML format</title>
    <description>
    This was an attempt to create a generic XML format to store roleplaying 
    information. The package contains an XML schema, XSL Transformation 
    stylesheets and sample data (character descriptions from a "Feng Shui"
    and an "Unknown Armies" campaign). I doubt that this project will go
    any further, but you may use the ideas if you like.<br/>
    You'll need an XSLT engine to do the stylesheet transformations.
    </description>
    <link target="downloads/gameXF.zip">.zip</link>
</item>

<item>
    <title>LIRP-Zubehör (German language)</title>
    <description>
    Dies sind "Charakterb&#246;gen" f&#252;r ein LIRP (Life Indoor Roleplaying 
    Game) das wir auf einer Party durchgeführt haben. Jeder Gast erhielt
    einen solchen Zettel als Characterbeschreibung. Leider habe ich keine
    Aufschrieb des "Drumherums" und der restlichen Charactere mehr.
    </description>
    <link target="downloads/lirp.zip">OpenOffice Dokumente als .zip</link>
</item>

</downloadlist>
