<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<diary>
    <entry date="21.05.2001">
        Flight off Frankfurt. Some creep kept complaining because we were sent to 
        the wrong gate and the flight was late. I also found out that the guy at    
        the desk not only didn't really speak English or German, he also tried to 
        squeeze my 2 meters in a standard row, obviously because he wasn't able how
        to book a seat with extra leg room. Fortunately the flight wasn't booked 
        out and I had the row all to myself.
    </entry>
    <entry date="22.05.2001">   
        Anne picked me up at the airport, and we took the Bus and subway to her
        apartment in Tamsui. Another friend of Anne, J&#246;rn, was also 
        visiting, and we went to a restaurant that night. It was one of those
        were you pick your raw ingredients and sauces from a buffet and then
        cook them yourself at the table; each table was cleverly equipped with
        a built-in gas stove for that purpose. 
    </entry>
    <entry date="23.05.2001">
        I went with J&#246;rn to visit the Chinan temple outside Taipeh. 
        Obviously this temple is also called "the temple of the thousand 
        stairs", hinting at the 1200 stairs you have to climb before reaching 
        the temple. And we actually saw a freak who was jogging up and down a
        flight of stairs in the blazing sun at about 40 degrees celsius. When we
        finally reached the temple, covered in sweat, we saw that some of the
        Taiwanese had just driven up the other side in electric golf cars.
        <p>
        Finding the temple was a little tricky, but a local showed us the way. 
        He actually led us up to the beginning of the stairs because we didn't
        understand any of his chinese explanations. People really seem to 
        be friendly here. We also had a chat with someone on the way up when 
        J&#246;rn was photographing some puppies.
        </p>
        <p>
        The Taoist temple was large, heavily ornamented and bustling with life.
        There were several stalls in the entrance area, selling incense and 
        other stuff neccessary for Taoist worship. The Budhist temple was 
        more tranquil and less freqented, allowing us to relax a bit.
        </p>
        <p>
        We got back into the city for lunch and chose one of the omnipresent
        small eateries. We didn't understand a word of the menu, but it turned
        out that one of the patrons spoke german (of all languages). He 
        explained that this place's speciality were different makes of a kind
        of suid soup. He ordered two bowls for us and even fixed the price.
        We saw some more temples after lunch, and in one of the smaller temples
        the caretaker took the time of explaining all the deities to us.
        </p>
        <p>
        Later on I got my first sample of food from the Tamsui night market: 
        fries from sweet potatoes, a soup made with pork bowels and some cold
        tea with milk and tiny, gucky balls in it (I later learned that in 
        Australia this is also know as "pearl tea".)
        </p>
    </entry>
    <entry date="24.05.2001">
        I missed J&#246;rn and A-Ga (another friend of Anne), mainly because the 
        apartment had no doorbell and J&#246;rn didn't have my mobile number.
        This meant I had to spend the day alone, so I strolled around Tamsui, 
        went down to the "shore" and then took the metro downtown. I checked
        out some shops with cameras and other gizmos, and discovered a nice
        inner-city park. Food was: Grilled skewers with different vegetables,
        pork, bloody rice. I managed to tea without gelatinous globules.
    </entry>
    <entry date="25.05.2001">
        J&#246;rn left for the Taroko valley today. I went to the Kuandu temple
        which Anne recommended as one of the places were you can actually go 
        and relax in Taipeh. There is a small park behind the temple where you
        can sit in the shadows of the trees, sit, read or have a nap. The little
        kids in the temple seemed fascinated by me, especially when they found
        out that I could actually talk. 
        <p>
        I went to a food stall on the street next to the temple - my fist 
        attempt at getting fed without knowing a single word of chinese.
        Fortunately it only took some pointing and the owners completed the
        order for me, giving me a full meal. They were were friendly, and 
        I even got a bottle of coke for free. They were also quite intrigued
        by today's only western customer and I guess I looked quite funny 
        picking with my chopsticks and at the same time having the flimsy 
        plastic bowl blown over by the wind. 
        </p>
        <p>
        After that I went downtown to see some more temples (the Pao-An and
        the Confuscius temple), and later visited an internet cafe to check
        my mail and pass the time while waiting for Anne. The cafe is quite
        cheap, has excellent net access and is load like hell. Not only are
        they constantly playing some kind of music, there are also about 100
        teenagers playing "Counter Strike" all the time. It sounds like a war
        zone.
        </p>
        <p>
        I was at the night market with Anne, and we went to a small, greasy
        place where they supposedly made the best dumplings in this part of
        town. We also got some more of the sweet potatoe fries and some 
        funny envelopes and letter paper. The letter paper actually deserves
        a special note: It seems that postcards are somewhat unpupolar in
        Taiwan (I only saw them at dedicated tourist joints), but they have
        an abundance of funny letter sets with matching envelope and paper.
        Most of the packs are quite elaborate, and incredibly tacky by western
        standards. I even got a set where the envelopes folded up to a small
        pill-box into which you inserted a letter written on pill-shaped paper.
        I really loved the idea - much cooler than postcards - so we went on
        a shopping spree and I got at least five sets.
        </p>
        <p>
        I also witnessed another Taiwanese attraction today: Garbage collection.
        There are no rubbish bins in the street (because they'd be unhygenic)
        and you must personally take down your waste to the garbage truck 
        when it comes along. The truck plays a loud tune to let everybody in the
        street know that it is time to dispose of your rubbish. Once you hear 
        this music, you bring your stuff downstairs and have a chance to meet
        all your neighbors and have a nice chat. A particular highlight is the
        recycling truck - instead of the tune it will play a kind of chant that,
        as Anne told me, enumerates the things you are supposed to recycle.
        </p>
    </entry>
    <entry date="26.05.2001">
        We had time for a more elaborate breakfast today (pancaces - slightly
        too dark ;-) - fruits and little rice cakes. Since Anne wasn't working
        all day, we wen't to the jade- and flowermarkets in the city. Although
        they were already closing down, there was still a lot to see, even 
        we didn't buy anything. 
        <p>
        We went to a McDonalds, sat a while at the huge square in front of the
        CKS (Chian Kaishek) memorial and then decided to see the local Toys'R'us
        - my idea. When we were trying to find the way on the map in the
        subway station a woman asked us if she could help, called a taxi over and
        told the driver to get us to the shop. I'm still amazed how friendly the
        people are. 
        </p>
        <p>
        The Toys'R'us visit went as expected: Anne came out with a bag of knead,
        a yo-you (including an instructional video, amongst other things) and an
        electric crab that was supposed to walk up slick walls. I got a Nerf gun
        and some darts (wohoo!). We ate in a japanese fast-food place where we 
        unpacked our stuff and started playing...
        </p>
    </entry>
    <entry date="27.05.2001">
        Since Anne doesn't have to work we try to visit the "Movie Museum", only
        to find out that it will only open next year or so. Since we're already
        downtown we decide to shop for useless things. Anne ends up with some
        japanese wooden shoes and tacky letter sets, while I get some tacky 
        letter sets and a DVD. To celebrate we go to another japanese place were
        they grill the stuff in front of your place on a hot stone.
    </entry>
    <entry date="28.05.2001">
        Anne is back to work, so I'm on my own again. I miss the memorial that
        I was looking for and went for the CKS memorial instead (hard to miss).
        It was quite interesting, even if the whole thing was - naturally -
        something like a Chiang Kaishek fan shop and I was to late to see the
        presentational video. Still, it's amazing that most of the time you 
        don't even realize how little you know about other peoples' history.
        The memorial also featured the obligatory honour guard, including the
        inevitable "changing of the guard" ritual. At night we got some food
        from the night market again.
    </entry>
    <entry date="29.05.2001">
        Finally found the Sun Yatsen memorial today. Even though there wasn't
        any sign of the photo exhibition mentioned in the travel guide they 
        did have a nice exhibition of contemporary arts. I like the work with
        photos of students doing "raids" with pink bubble guns.
        <p>
        Later in the day Anne and I went for another night market spree. 
        Results: Daniel: Two more packs of tacky letter paper. Anne:
        The Afro-Ken button, Afro-Ken bag, Afro-Ken filofax calendar, Afro-Ken
        notebook and Afro-Ken letter paper. She also got a little Sesame Street 
        case. Anne wins and is now totaly Afro-Ken'd. We also got some 
        interesting new (well, new to me) food from the night market: 
        Fried steaks and a kind of 
        pancaces filled with some kind of cabbage and a sweet nut paste. Also
        dumplings and meat and vegetables in a strangely gelatinous pastry.
        </p>
    </entry>
    <entry date="30.05.2001">
        Today Anne took me to sample a local speciality of Tamsui: A big 
        tofu dumpling in a special sauce, filled with meat or fish and called
        "A-ge" or something. For dessert
        we had a kind of soy-based vanilla pudding with sweet sauce and the
        omnipresent gucky balls (the ones from the tea) - sweet but good. 
        And we went to two different places to get the best "A-ge" and 
        pudding. The "best place" concept seems to be quite big in Taiwan.
        <p>
        In the afternoon I went to the Fine Arts Museum, a state museum for 
        contemporary art. Some of the exhibits were probably less than 
        spectacular, but others were quite interesting and they had a good
        special exhibition by a british artist.
        </p>
        <p>
        Somehow I already lost the umbrella that I only bought this morning. 
        </p>
    </entry>
    <entry date="31.05.2001">
        Saw the National Palace today (not much to see, but a little art exhibition
        as will), and then spent a while browsing a book store. To bad I can't 
        read a word (or symbol?) chinese.
        <p>
        J&#246;rn is back from his trip. My return flight is on the 12th - 
        I should probably also get started when I want to see some more of the 
        country. 
        </p>
        <p>
        Some new food from the night market: A kind of waffles filled with sweet
        red beans. Also some frozen yoghurt with crushed ice.
        </p>
    </entry>
    <entry date="01.06.2001">
        I took the ferry to the other side to other side of the bay in Tamsui
        today and climbed the mountain there. I was quite proud to get up there
        in the heat, but Anne was less than impressed and maintained it was only
        a beginner's hill. In hindsight, she may well be right.
        <p>
        On my way up the hill I was invited to tee by some men who were 
        renovating it (or living there, I really couldn't tell). One of them
        obviously had worked in Germany for a while, and I was flabbergasted by
        their hospitality. 
        </p>
        <p>
        I also found that Taiwanese people fall into two groups, 
        hill-climbing-wise: One will simply take the car, drive up the
        road on the back of the montain, bring a gas stove and everything
        for an elaborate picnic. The other group will jog up the hill in
        high speed and then do some pull-ups on the top, just in case. 
        There doesn't seem to be anything in between. 
        </p>
        <p>
        Anne has a cold, but we still managed to get to the 
        Taiwanese-Western steakhose. One of the waiters even spoke a little
        german.
        </p>
    </entry>
    <entry date="02.06.2001">
        Anne just went to the library to get some books and then called in sick.
        I went to the jade- and flowermarket again with J&#246;rn, I want to
        get a chinese name stamp as a souvenir. They had a really cool dragon,
        but it's NT$18,000 (more than 1000 DM (&euro;500) at the time), so it's
        out of discussion.
    </entry>
    <entry date="03.06.2001">
        Went to the book shop with Anne and J&#246;rn. Anne went home
        again, her cold hasn't gotten better. I returned to the Jade market
        and got a "Han Da-Ning" name stamp made. It's not real jade, but
        it's still way too expensive.
        <p>
        Spent too long in the Internet cafe so the night market was already
        closing down and I couldn't get proper food. So Anne and I had to feed
        on junk from the 7-Eleven. Shame on me.
        </p>
    </entry>
    <entry date="04.06.2001">
        Finally started my trip to other parts of the country today. I took 
        off for the Taroko gorge at 8:00, taking the train to Hualien (4 hours)
        and then the bus to Tienhsiang (1.5 hours). A lot of driving for only
        200km, but especially the bus ride through the beautiful 
        gorge was really worth it.
        <p>
        The "simple" room in the catholic hostel is really simple, but only
        NT$800 per night. And it <i>does</i> have a ventilator.
        </p>
    </entry>
    <entry date="05.06.2001">
        I only did two smaller hikes in the gorge, but the landscape is simply
        amazing: Steep montains on both sides, covered with lush forests, and
        waterfalls springing up in the forests. I met a group of girls from
        a catholic seminar (the were actually singing "Ye-Tzu Halleluja" - in
        chinese). 
        <p>
        There was also met a professor of geophisics from San Francisco with his wife
        (she was Taiwanese) who happened to have studied in Karlsruhe for a 
        few years. And there was this business student who was glad to practice
        his English talking with me, and I was glad not be limited to pointing
        and smiling all the time.
        </p>
        <p>
        Got a mild case of dirrahoea too, this probably has something to do with
        the leafy stuff I got from the theologists...
        </p>
        <p>
        Went up to the hot springs, conveniently forgetting my swimming shorts,
        so I just climbed around and took some photos off the various bridges. 
        It also started raining today and was so hot and wet that I was covered
        in sweat for the rest of the day.
        </p>
    </entry>
    <entry date="06.06.2001">
        Although the Taroko gorge is quite beautiful, I decide to move on. 
        I want to try to get a bus to Linshan in the center of the country
        where I should be able to find a room or a bus to Taichung on the 
        west coast. 
        <p>
        The trip didn't quite went as expected. After asking around at the
        bus station for a while I finally found a driver going into the 
        direction. (And, gladly enough, I didn't meet the rude guy from the
        trip up from Hualien again). If I interpreted his gestures correctly,
        the road to Lishan is somehow blocked, but he can get me to 
        Taichung - which is where I wanted to go anyway. He also seems to 
        be telling me that I must change the bus somewhere.
        </p>
        <p>
        The ride is quite spectacular: The bus is slowly climbing the tropic
        montains until you have an amazing view over the valleys and 
        cloud-shrouded peaks. The athmosphere is more like on a field trip,
        the driver's wive is selling food and organising everything, and when
        someone has to step out the bus'll stop at the next collection of huts.
        </p>
        <p>
        The bus finally reaches a small village, or rather a few food stalls,
        at a tunnel entrance on top of the montains. The driver beckons  me out,
        tries to tell me something on chinese an then starts to instruct an 
        elderly guy who looks more like a mongol chieftain or pirate than 
        anything else. He obviously tells him to get this clueless westerner
        on the right bus to Taichung, or at least I hope so. I eat something
        in one of the stalls, try to make "conversation" with the locals (I 
        <i>think</i> they're trying to speak english to me) and wait for the 
        bus. I'm still a little nervous: If something goes wrong I'm stuck in 
        the middle of nowhere for at least a day, and I'm quite certain there
        aren't any rooms to rent here...
        </p>
        <p>
        After a while, van-sized bus arrives, and the old guy ushers me in. 
        Seems like my worries are unfounded: The bus driver let's me out
        exactly in front of the Hotel I was looking for. And I didn't
        even have to pay for the second bus. The hotel is a little
        more expensive than the thing in Tienhsiang, but at least I got my own
        bathroom, TV, air conditioning and a room that's larger than the bed.
        </p>
        <p>
        Took a stroll through Taichung at night and visited another Internet
        cafe. A guy seemed to tried to make fun of me by asking me where I was
        from and telling me he's "Chief of Foreign Office Police Division". 
        Probably just a jerk, but still spoiling my mood. But never mind,
        everything else went just fine today, so I'm probably just a little
        edgy after the long trip.
        </p>
    </entry>
    <entry date="07.06.2001">
        Decided to move on to Alishan, a popular tourist destination. The 
        express train to Chiayi is already waiting at the station, and
        it only takes an hour to get there. I opt for the "scenic train" that
        goes up into the montains to Alishan since it's recommended by the
        guide and seems more hassle-free than finding a bus.
        <p>
        Once on the train I've to swap places for a few times, Taiwanese seem
        really big on seat reservations. The view is really scenic, at least
        until the train stops dead in a tunnel. After trying to suffocate us
        with the diesel exhaust for a while it reverses and moves out of
        the tunnel again. The passengers don't seem particularly bothered, they
        get off the train, take out their cameras and take photos of each other.
        The train attendants are calling someone on their mobile phones.
        </p>
        <p>
        The train finally get's back the last station, were some a announcement
        is made (chinese only) and everybody gets off and starts running around.
        I ask a student couple what all this is about, and they tell me there
        has been a landside on the other side of the tunnel, and we'll all be
        taken to Alishan by bus. The two are called Tony and Luna, he's a  
        business student and has to join the army soon, and she's japanese
        and will start working for a company in Austria soon. The two help
        me with the hotel and take me for dinner in the evening.
        </p>
        <p>
        Alishan is really a tourist place, everything is expensive: The (bad)
        food NT$500, NT$800 for the mediocre room and another NT$400 for
        the "scenic train" (the express from Taichung was only NT$300).
        </p>
    </entry>
    <entry date="08.06.2001">
        The hotel staff wakes me at 3:00 for the main attraction: Sunrise
        on Wushan montain. I wasn't exactly overwhelmed by the sunrise, even
        if it seems to be the thing here. The best part of this episode was
        the dog who led me up the montain in the twilight. I didn't see many
        of the Taiwanese guests either, although everybody was going: They
        all took the train or vans to the top of the montain and never strayed
        more than 200 meters from the train station. 
        <p>
        After a small hike around the mountains I decide that there's not much
        more to see in Alishan. Since the train isn't running any more I 
        have to take the bus, wich careens quite a bit when taking me down
        the steep hills back to Chiyi. 
        </p>
        <p>
        In the train to Tainan I meet a young local who tells me a bit about
        himself and the city. The hotel is cheap, but a bit run-down: The
        paint is coming off, the air conditioning is broken and the bathtub
        is holey. I take a quick stroll into the city, planning to go to bed 
        early but can't sleep until late at night.
        </p>
    </entry>
    <entry date="09.06.2001">
        Visited the major sights of Tainan, and tried the local speciality, 
        a kind of meatballs. The ice is also famous, but the place I find is
        too crowded so I don't try it.
        <p>
        After looking for some more temples I get the express train, which
        takes me back to Taipeh in four hours.
        </p>
    </entry>
    <entry date="10.06.2001">
        Anne had an mountaineering excercise today, which bascally consisted
        in carrying a 20kg backpack up some montains. I had myself carried up
        Taiwan's tallest building. After taking some pictures from above I
        went to Toys'R'Us again, but they were renovating and one couldn't find
        anything. I also saw the TFAM museum shop and then went to dinner with 
        Anne and some of her chinese montaineering friends. Nearly forgot my
        backpack in the restaurant.
    </entry>
    <entry date="11.06.2001">
        Finished reading Anne's book; "Opernball". Did some last minute 
        business: Shopping for red muck - to be used with the name seal - and
        went to the Lushan temple again to take some pictures.
        <p>
        A last night out on the night markets with Anne. She and her friend
        tried translating menu of the tea stall: "Purple Potatoe", "Um ... a 
        kind of plant" and "Milk under fire in the west" (Anne's try). Results
        of tonight's shopping: Anne: Some litter for the hamster, some hamster
        snacks, a flashlight with a funnily translated manual and a giant 
        Snoopy. Me: A suprise bag for Jan, various chinese snack products,
        tea, medical chewing stuff of oranges and herbs (good for a sore 
        throat) and funny signs (we actually still use the "cleaning" one). 
        After shopping it was time to pack up.
        </p>
    </entry>
    <entry date="12.06.2001">
        Finished packing my backpack, then went downtown one last time. Hillary,
        Anne's friend from NY is involved in setting up a new museum for
        contemporary art. The place is quite small, but the exhibits are very
        good - exactly the stuff I like. Plus Hillary explains everything, and
        visiting a museum is much nicer if you have someone to talk about the 
        art. They also set up a cool "internet" cafe.
        <p>
        Sadly enough, I learn that Prof. Liedtke of my home university died
        unexpectedly on the flight back from a conference in the US.
        </p>
        <p>
        Anne took me to the airport and saw me off. The trip home was quite
        uneventful, except that the Taipeh ground staff completely messed
        up the seating: I changed seats 4 times in order to reunite some
        family and <i>still</i> didn't get a seat with any leg room. The
        "we're ISO 9001 certified" boarding pass is one of my funniest
        souvenirs from that trip.
        </p>
        <p>
        Finally getting a set at the emergency exit proved to be a reunion with
        European customs: Even after explaining my predicament, some smallish
        german guy refused to give up his seat because "he already sat so tight
        on the flight here". Prick.
        </p>
    </entry>
<diary>