<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<diary>
    <entry date="20.10.2000">
        Packed up and left for San Francisco. Getting to La Guardia airport 
        wasn't the proble, however that didn't mean the flight was actually
        leaving there. Due to "technical difficulties" in SF, our connection
        flight was cancelled and we were put on an direct flight from JFK.
        <p>
        The airline did even provide a free bus to JFK, although they couldn't
        convince the driver to miss any of his regular stops. When it became 
        clear that we wouldn't make it in time a german-american woman went
        ballistic and started calling the driver names. Another passenger 
        called ahead to the airport and found out that the plane wouldn't
        wait for us, but was late anyway. In the end the bus was about
        45 minutes late, what was right on time to get on the plane
        without having to wait. We didn't even lose time, because there
        was no changing and waiting for the connecting flight now.
        </p>
        <p>
        Psycho picked us up at the airport. We checked out, got our rental
        car and a ridiculously expensive parking lot near our hotel. The
        hotel was typical "budget" accomodation for a big city: More like
        a hostel, and still pricey (though cheap, compared to the rest).
        </p>
        <p>
        Psycho brought some canned Guiness to celebrate our reunion, and
        we even found an irish pub later on. Guess what, the third round
        was on the house.
        </p>
    </entry>
    <entry date="21.11.2000">
        We droved up to the ? tower in the morning, enjoyed the view over
	the bay and walked around the neighborhood. Didn't take a cable
	car, though.
	<p>
	Psycho had tickets pre-ordered for Micha and me to see THE ROCK up
	close - visit to Alcatraz including the self-guided audio tour. 
	The place is still imposing, too bad I didn't learn much about the
	indian demonstration that took place there.
	</p>
	<p>
	After returning from Alcatraz we got some food and had a picknick
	on the hill on the other side of the Golden Gate. We didn't have
	to wait long before the Imperial Star Troopers showed up. The
	real Star Wars stuff, helmet and all - a photo session of some
	Star Trek Geeks. 
	</p>
	<p>
	Evening programme: The Sony center for admiring the newest gizmos and
	a movie in the cineplex.
	</p>
    </entry>
    <entry date="22.11.2000">
    	Started the day relaxing in the park, and later saw the SF Museum of
	Modern arts. Even Micha and Psycho went, although they aren't much
	into modern art most of the time. Uli and I had a fun time.
	<p>
	Psycho also showed us to SF's "second best" burger restaurant, to sample
	real american delicacies.
	</p>
    </entry>
</diary>
